suppose we start with a regular pentagon
and let's assume the side length is one
the diagonal length that cuts across the
Pentagon here is well known to have a
length given by the Golden Ratio
fee another well-known fact about the
regular pentagon is that this diagonal
shown here along with the original
diagonal drawn creates an isoceles
triangle as pictured here which has
sides of length one and a base of length
1 divided by the golden ratio to see a
proof of this fact check the video
Linked In the description the purple
shaded triangle shown in this diagram is
known as the Golden Triangle the outer
containing triangle is often referred to
as the golden
nomon now we scale the Golden Triangle
by the value one over the Golden Ratio
this allows us to fit a new triangle
right next to the original with sides of
length 1 over the golden ratio and base
given by 1 over the golden ratio squar
this is actually just another Golden
Triangle as it's similar to the original
but now we can repeat this process
scaling the new triangle by one over the
golden ratio and rotating it and fitting
it in the empty space and continuing
again scaling by one over the golden
ratio and fitting the new triangle in
the empty space we can continue this
process
indefinitely each stage we take the
previously scaled copy of the Golden
Triangle and scale Again by the value 1
divid by the Golden Ratio rotate and fit
it in the empty space if we imagine that
we let this process go on forever or
infinitely often the limiting shape is
the entire golden Noman and that means
that we've filled in the entire golden
Noman with these scaled golden triangles
but then we can compute the length of
the long side of the golden Noman
triangle two different ways we know that
on the one hand it's given by the golden
ratio on the other hand it's given by
the sum of the the lengths of the purple
Golden Triangle sitting inside but each
of those purple triangles has a length
given by 1 over an even power of the
golden ratio this means that the golden
ratio is equal to the infinite sum of
the reciprocals of the even powers of
the golden ratio as shown here but we
can also get a related fact by looking
at the pink shaded Golden Triangle
sitting inside this golden nomon on the
one hand the side of the golden nomon
has a length one on the other hand it's
also given by the sum of the lengths of
the pink shaded triangles sitting inside
but each of the pink shaded triangles
has a length given by one over an odd
power of the golden ratio therefore one
is equal to the infinite sum of the
reciprocal of the odd powers of the
golden ratio notice that these two facts
are actually one and the same as we can
obtain the first fact from the second
fact simply by multiplying the entire
equality by the Golden Ratio Fe either
of these two infinite series could be
called the Golden series as they deal
with the infinite powers of the
reciprocal of the golden ratio can you
see what happens if you try to add up
all of the powers of the reciprocal of
the golden ratio